Fund for Adult Education (FAE) Records
Fund for Adult Education (FAE) Records
1950-1969
Fund for Adult Education (U.S.)
70 linear ft.
The Fund for Adult Education was a subsidiary foundation established and supported by the Ford Foundation. Founded in 1951, its purposes were to aid and encourage liberal adult education in political, economic, and international affairs and in the humanities, with an emphasis on study-discussion. It became instrumental in the establishment of an educational broadcasting system (ETV) in the United States. The Fund officially ended its activities in 1961. Records include correspondence, published material, reports, and work files. Best represented in the collection are the Fund's Test Cities, "Great Men, Great Issues," "Meet the Humanities," "Ways of Mankind" and Experimental discussion Projects.
148993
Biographical History
The Fund for Adult Education (FAE) was a subsidiary foundation established and supported by the Ford Foundation. Founded in 1951, the Fund had as its purpose to aid and to encourage liberal adult education especially in political, economic, and international affairs and the humanities, with emphasis on study-discussion. However, because of the coincidence of history, the Fund became the main instrument in the establishment of an educational broadcasting system (particularly ETV) in the United States. The Fund had its own board of directors and staff, and it was both a grant-giving and an operating organization. During its early years, the Fund financed the sometimes controversial Test Cities experiment, the purpose of which was to ascertain the best ways to coordinate and stimulate adult education activities, community by community. The Test Cities Project involved individuals and institutions in thirteen United States communities in an experimental and novel educational project. Each of the participating Test Cities programs was independent of the Fund and controlled its own programs. The Fund officially ended its activities in 1961, although it continued as a legal entity (just as some of the projects to which it gave long-term grants continued) after 1961. Description
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Fund for Adult Education (FAE) Records contain correspondence, published material, reports, and work files of Fund projects that date from 1950, the year prior to the organization's founding. Bull: dates of the collection are 1951 to 1958, although some printed material dates to 1969. The collection is arranged by broad subject categories in 97 boxes and one package that total 70 linear feet. Most of the collection deals with Fund-operated projects, mainly study-discussion programs.
Boxes 1-31 contain the files of the Fund's Test Cities experiment. The first five boxes contain general files, largely correspondence, but there are also there are files, arranged by community name, of the projects undertaken in the thirteen communities that were involved in the program. These latter files typically contain correspondence, project histories, newsletters, reports, and news-clippings. A restriction on research access to the Fund for Adult Education Test Cities files, specified by the donor, limits access to professional persons in the field of educational history and research and further stipulates that no quotation from any letter, memorandum, report, or any other document in the Test Cities files be made without the written permission of the person who made the document.
Data on the three projects, " Great Men, Great Issues," " Meet the Humanities," and " Ways of Mankind," will be found in boxes 32-44. Most of the folders are geographical, as are the folders of the Experimental discussion Project (EDP), arranged under discussion topics in boxes 44-76, which contain the evaluations of the study-discussion program materials that evolved in the Fund's Experimental discussion Project. This project helped develop liberal arts and science courses that were designed for small groups led by properly trained lay leaders who were not necessarily either professional educators or subject specialists. The study-discussion programs were conducted with experimental groups, and on the basis of criticisms received from these groups, program materials were revised and then distributed at a nominal cost to groups throughout the country. These EDP files are the rough evaluations from which the Fund worked in revising the program materials. The story of the Experimental discussion Project is told in the report by Glen Burch, "Accent on Learning."
Boxes 77-97 contain files under the headings of Personal Information, Group Information, and Group Leaders' Reactions, as well as newspaper clippings, photostats, and printed material. Newsclippings and photostats are mounted in bound volumes, rather than placed in folders. In the Fund for Adult Education Papers there is no overall report of Fund activities; the closest approximation to one is " The Challenge of Lifetime Learning: Continuing Liberal Education, report 1955-1957," a copy of which is located in box 97. Further details on the holdings of the collection are available in the accompanying shelf list, which has been prepared from folder headings of the Fund for Adult Education Papers as they were processed prior to their arrival in the Manuscripts Division.
Audiorecordings consists of more than 100 audiorecordings pertaining to various projects, including "Ways of Mankind," "People Under Communism," and "Jeffersonian Heritage."
Arrangement of the Collection
The material is largely arranged as received.
Related Material
The library holds a considerable number of collections related to adult and continuing education. Please refer to for a complete listing.
The following collections may be of particular interest:
Individuals
Hendrickson, Andrew
Jacques, Joseph
Liveright, Alexander A.
Sheats, Paul.
Organizations
Adult Education Association (AEA)
American Foundation for Continuing Education (AFCE)
Association of University Evening Colleges (AUEC)
Center for the Study of Liberal Education for Adults (CSLEA)
National Association of Public School Adult Educators (NAPSAE)
National University Extension Association (NUEA)
Subject and Genre Headings
Adult education; Fund for Adult Education (U.S.) -- Archives; Fund for Adult Education (U.S.) -- Records and correspondence.; Adult education.; Community education -- United States; 35mm (photographic film size); Audiocassettes.; Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Film reels.; Phonograph records.; Reports.; Educators.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Additional access restrictions lifted, 2006.
Acquisition Information
Gift of the Fund for Adult Education, 1961, with subsequent additions
Inventory
- Test Cities
  - General
    - General correspondence, Jul 1951-Oct 1954; 8 folders (Box 1)
    - General correspondence, Nov 1954-Mar 1957; 5 folders (Box 2)
    - Program correspondence, Jan 1952-Jul 1952 (Box 2)
    - Allerton House Conference, 1953-1954 (Box 2)
    - Colorado Conference, 1952 (Box 2)
    - Meeting, Rancho Santa Fe, 1955-1956 (Box 2)
    - Regional Conference, New York, 1954 (Box 2)
    - Advertising campaign, 1952-1953 (Box 3)
    - Evaluation reports, 1954 (Box 3)
    - Personnel file, coordinators, 1952-1956 (Box 3)
    - Memoranda on project, 1951-1952 (Box 3)
    - Project planning, 1951 (Box 3)
    - Surveys, preliminary, 1952; 3 folders (Box 3)
    - Bigwin Conference, Jul 1953-Sep 1953 (Box 3)
    - Bigwin, correspondence, Sep 1952-Jan 1955; 3 folders (Box 4)
    - Chattanooga survey of discussion group participants, 1953 (Box 4)
    - Bigwin
      - Conferences and reports, 1953-1954 (Box 4)
      - Newsletter, 1953 (Box 4)
      - Speeches, 1953-1954; 2 folders (Box 4)
        See also Drafts of Speeches.
      - Correspondence re film, May 1953-Mar 1954; 2 folders (Box 5)
      - Test City Profiles, 1954 (Box 5)
      - Drafts of speeches, 1954 (Box 5)
        See also Speeches.
      - Program Preparation, 1954 (Box 5)
      - Evaluations, 1954 (Box 5)
      - Miscellaneous, 1954 (Box 5)
      - Clippings, 1954 (Box 5)
      - Bigwin Inn Reel 1 Music [soundtrack], fae_105; 16mm film; magnet track; 200 feet (Oversize 1)
      - Bigwin Inn Reel 1 Narration [soundtrack], fae_107; 16mm film; magnet track; 400 feet (Oversize 1)
      - Bigwin Inn Reel 2 Narration [soundtrack], fae_108; 16mm film; magnet track; 400 feet (Oversize 1)
      - Bigwin Inn Reel 3 Music [soundtrack], fae_106; 16mm film; magnet track; 200 feet (Oversize 1)
      - Bigwin Inn Reel 3 Narration [soundtrack], fae_109; 16mm film; magnet track; 300 feet (Oversize 1)
      - Bigwin Inn Reel 4 Music [soundtrack], fae_111; 16mm film; magnet track; 50 feet (Oversize 1)
      - Bigwin Inn Reel 4 Narration [soundtrack], fae_110; 16mm film; magnet track; 25 feet (Oversize 1)
  - Test Cities: Akron
    - Correspondence, 1951-1957; 6 folders (Box 6)
    - Adult Education newsletter, 1953-1957 (Box 6)
    - Calendar of events, 1953-1954 (Box 6)
    - History of project, 1955 (Box 6)
    - Program, Community Leadership Institute, 1955 (Box 7)
    - Program, Design and You, 1954 (Box 7)
    - Program, Law Enforcement and the Citizen, 1955 (Box 7)
    - Program, World Affairs, 1955 (Box 7)
    - Programs and materials, 1953-1957; 5 folders (Box 8)
    - Reports, 1954-1958 (Box 8)
    - Reports, organizations, 1951-1953; 2 folders (Box 8)
    - Reports, organizations, 1954-1957; 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Test Cities: Bridgeport
    - Correspondence, 1952-1955; 4 folders (Box 9)
    - History of program, 1955 (Box 9)
    - Programs and materials, 1953-1955 (Box 9)
    - Reports, 1953-1955 (Box 9)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1953-1955 (Box 9)
  - Test Cities: Chattanooga
    - Correspondence, 1951-1960; 8 folders (Box 10)
    - Handbook, 1952 (Box 10)
    - Newsletter, 1952-1959 (Box 10)
    - Materials and announcements, 1952-1958; 2 folders (Box 10)
    - Project, "There Shall Be Peace, 1952 (Box 10)
    - Project reports, miscellaneous, 1953-1958 (Box 10)
    - Projects, ,iscellaneous, 1954-1956; 2 folders (Box 10)
    - Report on project, 1955 (Box 10)
    - Reports, Board of Directors, 1952-1958 (Box 12)
    - Reports, Quarterly and Annual, 1952-1957 (Box 12)
    - Report, "Education for Freedom, 1958 (Box 12)
    - Report, "Introduction to Poetry, 1956 (Box 12)
    - Reports, miscellaneous, 1952-1953 (Box 12)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1951-1960; 5 folders (Box 13)
  - Test Cities: Kansas City
    - Correspondence, 1952-1955; 4 folders (Box 14)
    - History of project, 1955 (Box 14)
    - Miscellaneous materials, vs. dates (Box 14)
    - Programs and materials, 1952-1955 (Box 14)
    - Reports, 1952-1955 (Box 14)
  - Test Cities: Little Rock
    - Correspondence, 1951-1955; 5 folders (Box 15)
    - History of project, 1955 (Box 15)
    - Adult Education Center, plans for, 1954 (Box 15)
    - Advertising cuts, 1953 (Box 15)
    - Materials, 1952-1955 (Box 15)
    - Quarterly summary reports, 1953-1955 (Box 15)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1951-1957 (Box 15)
  - Test Cities: Lubbock
    - Correspondence, 1951-1956; 3 folders (Box 16)
    - Materials, 1953-1955; 2 folders (Box 16)
    - Reports on program, 1952-1955 (Box 16)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1952-1954 (Box 16)
  - Test Cities: Memphis
    - Correspondence, 1953-1957; 3 folders (Box 16)
    - History of project, 1955 (Box 16)
    - Materials, correspondence re, 1954-1955 (Box 16)
    - Financial reports, 1954-1956 (Box 16)
    - Friedan report, Executive Leadership Program, 1957 (Box 16)
    - Institute for Executive Leadership, 1955-1957 (Box 16)
    - Newsletters, 1953-1957 (Box 16)
    - Printed materials, 1955 (Box 17)
    - Programs and materials, 1953-1958; 2 folders (Box 17)
    - Reports, 1953-1957; 2 folders (Box 17)
    - Newspaper clippings, miscellaneous, 1953-1956 (Box 17)
  - Test Cities: Niagara Falls
    - Correspondence, 1952-1960; 5 folders (Box 17)
    - History of project, 1955 (Box 18)
    - Community reports, 1952; 1954 (Box 18)
    - Newsletter, 1953-1955 (Box 18)
    - Pilot program, "Preparation for Retirement", 1956-1957 (Box 18)
    - Printed materials, 1954-1955; 2 folders (Box 18)
    - Programs and materials, 1953-1958; 3 folders (Box 18)
    - Quarterly reports, 1954-1957 (Box 18)
    - Miscellaneous reports, 1954-1957 (Box 18)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1952-1957; 4 folders (Box 19)
  - Test Cities: Racine
    - Correspondence, 1952-1955; 4 folders (Box 19)
    - Report on project, 1955 (Box 20)
    - Newsletter, 1953-1955 (Box 20)
    - Programs, printed material, 1953-1955 (Box 20)
    - Program, "Ways of Mankind", 1954 (Box 20)
    - Project in Racine, papers re, 1951 (Box 20)
    - Miscellaneous reports, Board of Directors, 1952-1954 (Box 20)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1952-1955; 2 folders (Box 20)
  - Test Cities: San Bernardino
    - Correspondence, 1951-1960; 6 folders (Box 21)
    - History of Test Cities Project, 1956 (Box 21)
    - The Community Education Project, 1956 (Box 21)
    - Discussion materials
      - "Jeffersonian Heritage, 1953 (Box 21)
        See also Audiorecordings.
      - "Living Generation", 1954 (Box 21)
      - "Ways of Mankind", 1953 (Box 22)
      - "The Years Between", 1954-1955 (Box 22)
    - Printed materials, 1952-1957 (Box 22)
    - Program materials
      - "Living Generation", 1954 (Box 22)
      - "Metroplex", 1955-1957; 2 folders (Box 22)
      - Miscellaneous, 1952-1954 (Box 23)
    - Program on "Urbanism, 1955 (Box 23)
    - Progress reports, 1952-1956; 2 folders (Box 23)
    - Newspaper clippings
      - General, 1951-1953 (Box 23)
      - "Ways of Mankind", 1953 (Box 23)
      - General, 1954; 1955 (Box 24)
      - "Metroplex", 1955-1956 (Box 24)
      - General, 1956-1957 (Box 24)
  - Test Cities: Sioux City
    - Correspondence, 1951-1961; 4 folders (Box 24)
    - History of Test City Project, 1955 (Box 24)
    - Printed material, 1952-1955; 3 folders (Box 25)
    - Reports, 1951-1956 (Box 25)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1951-1958; 2 folders (Box 25)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1954-1958; 2 folders (Box 26)
  - Test Cities: West Texas
    - Correspondence, 1950-1958; 5 folders (Box 27)
    - Report on the project, 1955 (Box 27)
    - Adult Education News, 1952-1957 (Box 28)
    - Conferences, 1956 (Box 28)
    - News releases, various dates (Box 28)
    - Miscellaneous papers, 1952-1956 (Box 28)
    - Program materials, 1952-1957 (Box 28)
    - Program materials, "Sing Your America", 1955 (Box 28)
    - Reports, 1952-1957 (Box 28)
    - Reports, Regional Development, 1954-1957; 2 folders (Box 29)
    - Reports, miscellaneous, 1952-1957 (Box 29)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1952-1954; 2 folders (Box 29)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1955-1958; 3 folders (Box 30)
  - Test Cities: York
    - Correspondence, 1952-1956; 4 folders (Box 30)
    - "Drama for discussion" program, undated; 2 folders (Box 31)
    - Reports and evaluations, 1953-1956 (Box 31)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1952-1955 (Box 31)
- Great Men-Great Issues
  - Group member reports
    - Abbeville, La., 1952 (Box 32)
    - Andover, Mass., 1951 (Box 32)
    - Asheboro, N.C., 1951 (Box 32)
    - Baltimore, Md., 1952 (Box 32)
    - Bicknell, Utah, 1952 (Box 32)
    - Bloomington, Ill., 1952 (Box 32)
    - Boston, Mass., 1951; 2 folders (Box 32)
    - Brooklyn, N.Y., 1951-1952 (Box 32)
    - Buffalo, N.Y., 1951 (Box 33)
    - Charlotte, N.C., 1951 (Box 33)
    - Cheyenne, Wyo., 1952 (Box 33)
    - Chicago, Ill., 1951 (Box 33)
    - Chillicothe, Mo., 1951 (Box 33)
    - Columbus, Ohio, 1951 (Box 33)
    - Columbus, Mo., 1951; 2 folders (Box 33)
    - Dallas, Texas, 1951 (Box 33)
    - Delaware, Ohio, 1951 (Box 33)
    - Des Moines, Iowa, 1951 (Box 34)
    - East Greenbush, N.Y., 1952 (Box 34)
    - East Penfield, N.Y., 1951-1952 (Box 34)
    - Fort Atkinson, Wisc., 1951 (Box 34)
    - Grand Rapids, Mich., 1951; 2 folders (Box 34)
    - Great Falls, Mont., 1951 (Box 34)
    - Griffin, Ga., 1951 (Box 34)
    - Hundred, W.Va., 1951 (Box 35)
    - Indio, Cal., 1952 (Box 35)
    - Lafayette, La., 1951 (Box 35)
    - Laramie, Wyo., 1951 (Box 35)
    - Lincoln, Neb., 1951 (Box 35)
    - Loa, Utah, 1952 (Box 35)
    - Magna, Utah, 1951 (Box 35)
    - Memphis, Tenn., 1951 (Box 35)
    - Milwaukee, Wisc., 1952 (Box 35)
    - Minneapolis, Minn., 1952 (Box 36)
    - New Philadelphia, Ohio, 1951 (Box 36)
    - New York City, 1951-1952 (Box 36)
    - Newark, N.J., 1951 (Box 36)
    - Petersburg, Va., 1951 (Box 36)
    - Philadelphia, Pa., 1951 (Box 36)
    - Portland, Ore., 1951 (Box 36)
    - Racine, Wisc., 1951 (Box 36)
    - Rochester, Minn., 1952 (Box 36)
    - Rockville Center, N.Y., 1952 (Box 37)
    - Roosevelt, Utah, 1952 (Box 37)
    - Salt Lake City, Utah, 1951 (Box 37)
    - San Jose, Calif., 1951 (Box 37)
    - Santa Barbara, Calif., 1952 (Box 37)
    - Santa Monica, Calif., 1951 (Box 37)
    - Shorewood, Wisc., 1952; 2 folders (Box 37)
    - Sioux City, Iowa, 1952 (Box 38)
    - Spokane, Wash., 1951-1952; 2 folders (Box 38)
    - Springfield, Mass., 1951-1952 (Box 38)
    - Urbana, Ill., 1951 (Box 38)
    - Worthington, Minn., 1951 (Box 38)
  - Report-Discussion Leaders
    - Pasadena, Calif., 1951; 2 folders (Box 39)
    - Pasadena, Calif., 1952 (Box 39)
    - San Bernardino, Calif., 1952 (Box 39)
    - San Jose, Calif., 1951-1952 (Box 39)
    - Tucson, Arizona, 1951 (Box 39)
    - Miscellaneous, 1952 (Box 39)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Miscellaneous tabulations, 1952 (Box 39)
    - Summary questionnaire, 1952; 4 folders (Box 40)
    - Evaluation tabulations, 1952 (Box 40)
- Meet The Humanities
  - Group member reports
    - Pasadena, Calif., 1954; 2 folders (Box 41)
    - Stephens College, 1953; 3 folders (Box 41)
  - Group member surveys
    - Pasadena, Cal., 1954 (Box 41)
- Ways Of Mankind
  - Group member reports
    - Akron, Ohio, 1954 (Box 42)
    - Baltimore, Md., 1953 (Box 42)
    - Bell, Cal., 1953 (Box 42)
    - Boston, Mass., 1953 (Box 42)
    - Chattanooga, Tenn., 1953 (Box 42)
    - Chicago, Ill., 1953 (Box 42)
    - Dundalk, Md., 1953 (Box 42)
    - Grafton, W.Va., 1953 (Box 42)
    - Great Falls, Mont., 1953 (Box 42)
    - La Crosse, Wisc., 1953 (Box 43)
    - Lincoln, Neb., 1953 (Box 43)
    - Little Rock, Ark., 1953 (Box 43)
    - Oneonta, Cal., 1953 (Box 43)
    - Pasadena, Cal., 1953 (Box 43)
    - Salt Lake City, Utah, 1953 (Box 43)
    - York, Pa., 1953 (Box 44)
  - Group member survey, Pasadena, Cal., 1953 (Box 44)
  - End-of-meeting evaluation forms, 1953 (Box 44)
- Experimental discussion Project
  See also FAE Part 2: 1991 additions: Experimental discussion groups
  - EDP (Experimental discussion Programs)
    - Ways of Mankind
      - Group member report, 1953-1954; 3 folders (Box 44)
    - Current Economic Problems
      - Alhambra, Cal., 1953 (Box 45)
    - Your Money and Your Life
      - Baltimore, Md., 1953-1954; 2 folders (Box 45)
      - Bigwin Inn, 1953 (Box 45)
      - Boston, Mass., 1953; 2 folders (Box 45)
      - Boston, Mass., 1954; 2 folders (Box 45)
      - Buffalo, N.Y., 1953 (Box 46)
      - Chattanooga, Tenn., 1954 (Box 46)
      - Chautauqua, N.Y., 1954 (Box 46)
      - Chippewa Falls, 1953 (Box 46)
      - Detroit, Mich., 1954; 2 folders (Box 46)
      - Flint, Mich., 1953 (Box 46)
      - Greensboro, N.C., 1954; 2 folders (Box 47)
      - Kansas City, Mo., 1954 (Box 47)
      - Little Rock, Ark., 1954 (Box 47)
      - Los Angeles, Cal., 1953; 4 folders (Box 47)
      - Los Angeles, Cal., 1954; 2 folders (Box 48)
      - Lubbock, Tex., 1954 (Box 48)
      - Memphis, Tenn., 1953-1954; 2 folders (Box 48)
      - Niagara Falls, N.Y., 1954 (Box 48)
      - Othello, Wash., 1954; 3 folders (Box 48)
      - Pasadena, Cal., 1953-1954; 4 folders (Box 49)
      - Riverhead, N.Y., 1954 (Box 49)
      - St. Louis, Mo., 1954; 2 folders (Box 49)
      - San Bernardino, Cal., 1954 (Box 50)
      - San Jose, Cal., 1954 (Box 50)
      - Santa Monica, Cal., 1954; 2 folders (Box 50)
      - Sonoma, Cal., 1953 (Box 50)
      - Attendance records, 1953 (Box 50)
      - Evaluation and forms, 1954 (Box 50)
      - Evaluation comments, by city, 1953
        - A-N, 2 folders (Box 50)
        - P-W (Box 51)
        - 5th/6th Meetings, 1954 (Box 51)
        - 7th/8th Meetings, 1954 (Box 51)
      - Evaluation, final comments, 1954 (Box 51)
      - Evaluation, correspondence and reports, 1953 (Box 51)
      - Evaluation follow-up sheets, 1954 (Box 51)
      - Evaluation summary questionnaire, 1953 (Box 51)
      - Summary tabulations, 1954; 2 folders (Box 51)
  - Law And Justice
    - Evaluation Forms, Othello, Wash., 1954 (Box 52)
  - EFDP (Experimental Film discussion Project)
    See also FAE Part 2: 1991 additions: Experimental Film discussion Project, Progress report 1952.
    - World Affairs Are Your Affairs
      - Newark, N.J., 1952; 2 folders (Box 52)
      - Participants' Reaction Sheets, 1952 (Box 52)
  - EDP
    - Education for a Free Society
      - Berkeley, Cal., 1957 (Box 52)
      - New York City, 1957 (Box 52)
      - White Plains, N.Y., 1957 (Box 52)
      - Evaluations, 1957-1958 (Box 52)
    - The Shape of Our Cities, Evaluations, 1957-1958 (Box 52)
    - Transition and Tension in Southeast Asia, New York and White Plains, N.Y.; Springfield, Mass., 1957 (Box 52)
    - Human Freedom
      - Baltimore, Md., 1953 (Box 53)
      - Chattanooga, Tenn., 1953 (Box 53)
      - Chicago, Ill., 1953 (Box 53)
      - Covington, Tenn., 1953 (Box 53)
      - Glen Rock, Pa., 1954 (Box 53)
      - Memphis, Tenn., 1953 (Box 53)
      - Monteagle, Tenn., 1953 (Box 53)
      - Niagara Falls, N.Y., 1953 (Box 53)
      - Pasadena, Cal., 1953 (Box 53)
      - Salt Lake City, Utah, 1953 (Box 53)
      - Santa Rosa, Cal., 1954 (Box 53)
      - Sonoma, Cal., 1953 (Box 53)
      - Evaluations of program, 1952-1953 (Box 54)
      - Evaluation forms, 1952-1954; 2 folders (Box 54)
    - Jackson Heritage, Group member report, Pasadena, Cal., 1954 (Box 54)
    - Jefferson and Our Times, evaluation forms
      - Chautauqua, N.Y., 1954 (Box 54)
      - Chattanooga, Tenn., 1954 (Box 54)
      - Des Moines, Iowa, 1954 (Box 54)
      - Lincoln, Neb., 1954 (Box 54)
      - Memphis, Tenn., 1954 (Box 55)
      - Menlo Park, Cal., 1954 (Box 55)
      - Monteagle, Tenn., 1954 (Box 55)
      - Pasadena, Cal., 1954; 3 folders (Box 55)
      - Racine, Wisc., 1954 (Box 55)
      - San Francisco, Cal., 1954 (Box 55)
      - San Jose, Cal., 1954 (Box 55)
      - Santa Barbara, Cal., 1954 (Box 55)
      - Santa Monica, Cal., 1954 (Box 55)
      - Setauket, N.Y., 1954 (Box 56)
      - Thomasville, Ga., 1954 (Box 56)
      - Miscellaneous, 1954 (Box 56)
    - You and Modern Art
      - Chino, Cal., 1953 (Box 56)
      - Long Beach, Cal., 1953; 2 folders (Box 56)
      - Los Angeles, Cal., 1953; 2 folders (Box 56)
      - Pasadena, Cal., 1953; 2 folders (Box 57)
      - Santa Monica, Cal., 1953; 2 folders (Box 57)
      - Group member report, 1953; 2 folders (Box 57)
      - Evaluations, 1953 (Box 57)
    - Citizen and Mass Media
      - Akron, Ohio, 1955 (Box 58)
      - Altadena, Cal., 1954 (Box 58)
      - Beverly Hills, Cal., 1955 (Box 58)
      - Columbus, Ohio, 1955; 3 folders (Box 58)
      - Laguna Beach, Cal., 1955 (Box 59)
      - Oakland, Cal., 1955 (Box 59)
      - Ontario, Cal., 1955 (Box 59)
      - Othello, Cal., 1955 (Box 59)
      - Evaluations, 1955 (Box 59)
    - You and the Mass Media, 1957; evaluations (Box 59)
    - Life Under Communism
      - Baltimore, Md., 1953; 3 folders (Box 60)
      - Chicago, Ill., 1953 (Box 60)
      - Cleveland, Ohio, 1953 (Box 60)
      - Columbia, Mo., 1953 (Box 60)
      - Dallas, Tex., 1953 (Box 60)
      - El Monte, Cal., 1953 (Box 60)
      - Flint, Mich., 1953 (Box 60)